I've been trading for a little bit over
six and a half years, and I've been as
successful as a profitable trader can
get for a little bit over four and a
half years. Now, if I were to lose all
of my money, all of my trading accounts,
even the strategy that got me to the
point where I am today that has made me
the seven eight figures in the markets,
and my goal would be to have a thousand
dollars reached every single day as
profits, this is exactly what I would
do. So, let's dive right into it. How
can you make a thousand dollars a day
day trading every single day? Well, I'm
going to set the record straight. I'm
going to give you the proper tonality on
how to do this. And I'm not going to
give you unrealistic expectations. And
I'm going to say this right now. It's
impossible for you to make a thousand
dollars every single day in the markets.
It's impossible for you to find perfect
trade setups five days a week that would
equivalent to a thousand dollars a day.
It's just not going to happen. Now, I
know I get it. I get it. The reason why
you clicked this video is for that. But,
I'm going to educate you on how you can
end up making a thousand dollars every
single day by not making a thousand
dollars every single day. You're like,
Alex, what what does that mean? Well,
it's because the goal is to not make a
thousand dollars every single day. The
goal is to make five thousand dollars at
the end of the week. Now, by you making
a five thousand dollars at the end of
the week, you reverse that math
backwards, that would be a thousand
dollars every single day. Now, the
beauty of this is you didn't have to
overexpose yourself to taking
unnecessary trades. You didn't have to
stress yourself out by forcing trades to
hit this goal every single day of
attempting to make a thousand dollars,
and you're taking the proper trade
setups. So, you are actually being
patient. You're actually sitting on your
hands and risking money on trades that
make sense, and not overexposing
yourself on trades that don't make any
sense because you have a goal that you
want to reach by the end of the trading
session. Now, if you take a different
approach to this, and it's like, okay,
my goal is to make five thousand dollars
at the end of the week. If I take one
trade setup that I risk a thousand
dollars on, and I get a one to five risk
to reward, well, there's your five
thousand dollars every single day by
only taking one trade rather than
breaking that down in five to 10 trades
where it is far more stressful and it is
very unlikely that you will end up
making the $1,000 every single day this
way. So, let me actually break down how
you can do this correctly. And the best
analogy that I like to set for this is
trading is very much like baseball. When
you go play the game of baseball, you're
sitting on home base and you're waiting
for the pitcher to throw you a ball.
He's going to throw you fastball,
curveball, knuckleball and your job as a
batter in a baseball game is to just hit
that ball as far as you can so you can
get a home run. Now, the difference in
between trading and playing actual
baseball is that in trading you have
unlimited amounts of pitches and you are
not forced by anybody, by any clock, by
any coach, by any team to swing at the
ball that comes. The goal is for you to
just sit there and wait for the perfect
pitch. Now, the problem with traders is
that they want to swing at every single
pitch that the pitcher throws their way.
And guess what ends up happening? They
end up striking out. Now, the correct
thing to do in order for you to win the
game is be very patient, stick at the
home base and swing at the right pitch
and that's how you get the home run. Not
swinging at every single opportunity
that you get. That's why traders fail
because they want to take every single
opportunity that the market gives them
because they believe there's endless
amounts of opportunity and they have to
capitalize after every single one and
that is completely false. You should
only capitalize off of the correct ones.
Will you miss one here and there? Sure,
but that's part of the process. You're
not meant to catch every single one. You
can't swing at every single pitch. You
need to take the correct one. So,
everything I've done up to this point
right now is just give you the proper
context on how to have the right mindset
to making a thousand dollars a day. The
goal is to not make a thousand dollars a
day by swinging at every single ball
that the pitcher throws your way. If I
have to wait three days for the pitcher
to give me a perfect straight ball right
in the box and I swing and I get the
home run, it's the same thing if I would
have swung at a hundred different balls,
potentially injured myself. The goal is
to get the home run, not swing at every
single ball. So, that's this is just me
putting you guys into context. Now, this
is the actual first step that you can do
when it comes to the technical analysis
and how to actually get to this goal of
making a thousand dollars every single
day. And this one gets overlooked by
every single trader, beginner,
intermediate, and even advanced traders
at times, just because traders get lost
in the heat of the moment. And this is
not buying at highs and not selling at
lows. Always wait for a retracement.
Now, what does that mean? Everybody
hears that there's massive volatility in
the markets and then they want to get
involved.
The move already happened. If the market
has just had a high push, you have to
wait for a retracement. Don't enter with
hype. Don't enter with FOMO, thinking
that you're going to miss the move. The
move already happened. You have to wait
for the retracement. What ends up
happening in crypto? Bitcoin hits an
all-time high, Bitcoin just breaks
100,000, everybody wants to buy at that
point. Why would you want to buy at the
highest point that it's ever been? Wait
for a retracement. This goes for the
lower time frames as well. Whenever you
see a big push happen, wait for a
retracement, wait for that discount, and
then you enter your trade. This goes for
scalp trades, day trades, swing trades.
You want to make sure that you can get
that discount on price, so you have a
better entry. You have to be very
patient and that is part of the game.
Waiting for that perfect ball to get
into that pocket, so you take the swing.
Don't just take the trade because you
see a bunch of people supposedly making
money off of the big move that has just
happened. Now, moving on to step two,
and this is more of something that you
need to not do. And by not doing this,
you're going to save yourself so much
money that you can't even fathom. And
that's going to be don't get stuck to a
daily bias or constantly change a bias
depending on how you wake up that
morning. I can't explain to you how many
times I see traders when they wake up
for London session or wake up for New
York session, they're like, "Today, I'm
going to find the reason to buy." Or
today, I'm going to find the reason to
sell.
People change the direction of the
market every single day they go trade,
which makes no sense to me. How can
Monday you want to be interested in
buys, Tuesday be interested in sells,
and Wednesday be back interested in
buys? This can be a very typical scalp
trading approach, and there's a reason
why the majority of scalp traders don't
succeed and why they have a very low win
rate and they're not successful. It's
because they're constantly changing
their bias. You need to understand what
the higher time frames are doing at the
beginning of the week. On Sunday, before
the market even opens, you do your
technical analysis, and you understand
where is the market going to be headed
for this week. If you can see that the
market will be headed downwards for the
entirety of the week, you find for
reasons to enter that direction. If you
see that it's going to go bullish, you
look for reasons for it to go that way.
You don't change your bias in the middle
of the week wanting to enter a little
bit of that countertrend trade or that
retracement just so you can feel like
you're getting involved. You need to
make sure that you stick to your plan.
If at the beginning of the week, you see
that EUR/USD needs a retracement to then
hit that new higher high by the end of
the week, you wait for that retracement
and you enter the continuation of the
market. Don't try and catch that little
bit of a retracement just to feel like
you're involved. So, don't change your
market direction how you feel that day
or how the fundamentals came out. The
technicals will always lead, and stick
to that. Don't change it every single
morning. And the best analogy that I can
put to this, going back to the baseball
analogy, and funny enough, I don't even
play baseball. I just It makes sense to
me, right? Now, you wake up today and
you want to swing with your left arm
going this way, but for some reason, it
didn't work or you didn't find any good
opportunities swinging this way. You
said, "You know what? Tomorrow, we're
going to come to the market and we're
going to swing this way. We're going to
swing with our right hand." And for
whatever reason, it doesn't work, and
then you go back to this side. Stay
consistent with whatever you're going to
be doing. And this goes for strategies,
this goes for market direction. This
just goes for everything in general.
Just because I don't find opportunities
in this direction, doesn't mean that I'm
now going to look for opportunities in
this direction. If it works based off of
statistics and what I have done in the
past, I'm going to stick to that. Now,
this has up the perfect conversation for
my third point. And this is probably the
most powerful and in-depth point on how
to hit your goal of making a thousand
dollars every single day. Because in
order for you to make this amount of
money, there is risk involved in it. And
in this risk involved, you need to have
a plan. And if you have a plan, part of
that plan is you need to be okay with
losing. Because in that plan, losing is
part of that plan. Alex, what do you
mean? I don't want to lose in trading.
Well, if you don't want to lose in
trading, you should not even get
involved. Because trading is part of the
game. You just need to accept that. So,
let me break this down.
A trading plan on average has a 50 to
60% win rate. This is a great win rate.
Now, people only think about winning.
People don't think that, okay, I might
lose 40 to 50% of the time with a 50 to
60% win rate.
In default, if you're going to win five,
six trades, you should have lost four,
five trades. Now, does that mean that
you cut these losses short? Does that
mean that you avoid these losses? Or
does that mean that they never happen?
All of the above are no.
You will take these losses. There's no
way of avoiding it. And you need to
accept it from the start. Now, the
perfect example that I can say to this
is And I this whenever I get on a call
with my students and I review their
trades, a very common issue that I see
is that traders try and find a reason to
cut their losses short. And I'm just
going to, you know, use an alias name
here. And I remember this from the call
from yesterday, actually. We're going to
call him Josh.
Josh was in a trade and he was in
drawdown. And as I'm reviewing his
trade, he asked me, he's like, "Hey,
Alex, what can I do right now
to avoid this loss?"
I'm like,
"What do you mean?" He's like, "Yeah, I
I don't want to lose this trade that I'm
in right now. It didn't go to my take
profit. I'm halfway through my stop
loss. How do I not take a loss here?
Well, I'm like one,
be Jesus and control the market, or two,
not trade at all. You cannot enter a
trade if you don't accept the loss. I
asked him, "What did you risk on this
trade?" And he said 100 bucks. And I
said, "Okay.
Were you prepared to lose this 100 bucks
in the beginning?" And he said, "Yes."
And I said, "Okay, so what is the
problem if you lose those 100 bucks now?
Now that the plan is not going according
to plan, that it didn't go to your take
profit, you're backing out on your plan.
You're backing out on your word. How
does that make any sense?"
And then he started realizing that what
he was just doing is acting out of
emotion, going against his plan, not
realizing that these losses are part of
the plan. That's why there's a
pre-calculated risk behind every single
trade. And a lot of traders try and
avoid that, try and find a reason on how
to not lose or how to minimize their
losses. You minimize your losses by
having that pre-calculated risk
management before you enter the trade.
Now, after that Josh realized it and
accepted his fate and ended up losing
the trade. There's nothing wrong with
that. He pre-calculated his risk. If he
was not okay with losing those 100
bucks, he should have never traded in
the first place. If you're not ready to
lose, do not trade. And this is very
important topic because people want to
play the game of baseball, for example,
and not lose or find every reason to
only look at the positives and not the
negatives of it. You can go play a game
and you can go get injured. The other
team could just outperform you and you
can lose. What are you going to do?
It's part of the game. You accept if you
go play a game of baseball, a game of
basketball, a game of football soccer
that you could lose. Why don't you
accept that if you enter a trade, you
could lose? Now, it doesn't mean that
you're going to lose forever. It doesn't
mean you're unsuccessful or you're not
going to make it out. It just means that
specific trade didn't work out. You move
on to the next one. If you go play a
game of basketball and you lose, are you
not going to go play a different game?
No, you're going to go play another game
pretend like that last one didn't
happen. You're going to learn from your
mistakes. You're going to realize that
you should pass the ball more, that you
should lay it up, that you should do
whatever you didn't do in that other
game to win.
It's the exact same thing in trading.
Whatever you did in the last trade that
led you to losing, and you didn't like
that feeling, you learn from it and then
you optimize on the next one. And that's
just if you lose because you lost the
game. But there might be times where you
lose a game because you get injured, the
weather is bad, the game has to get
called short because of whatever reason,
and you still end up losing for whatever
the reason is. Are you going to let that
affect your next game? No, you're going
to treat the next game as if it were to
be a new game, and you're going to start
fresh from that point and not drag
whatever the last game was. So, if you
lose because of an external factor,
whatever it is, or because of yourself,
you cannot drag that to the next thing.
You put it to the side and you move on
to the next thing. And part of that plan
on being a profitable trader is
obviously not winning every single
trade. So, you understand that losses
are going to happen, and you can't
expect for you to maximize every single
trade to its potential. I have traders
that come all the time and ask me to
review their trades, and they have a
trade that they catch a 1:2, 1:3
risk-reward, but they had the potential
to be a 1:5, 1:6. And they want to
figure out how they can maximize that
trade. And I ask them, "Well, if part of
your trading plan was to get a 1:2, 1:3,
you close out there, you move on to the
next trade. Is it cool to maximize it
once in a blue moon? Yes, but you can't
optimize for that every single time.
It's not scalable." And I like using the
baseball analogy for this, and it's my
favorite one.
Your goal as a baseball player, when you
are at home base, is to swing as hard as
you can, get that ball as far as you
can, and go from first base, second
base, third base, and home. Now, a
baseball player's plan, or at least my
plan if I were to be a baseball player,
is going to be to every single time I
swing, I make sure this swing can get me
at least to second base. Not first base,
not third base, not second base. Now, I
take that directly to trading as a
perfect correlation. Every single trade
that I take has a minimum of a 1:2 risk
to reward. Why? Well, because it's a
positive risk reward. If I lose five
trades out of 10, I lose minus five, but
if these five trades I win plus two, I
just made back my five losses and I'm
positive another five by just having a
50% win rate. So, your goal as a trader
has to be exactly the same thing of a
baseball player.
When you go, make sure that you're going
to swing as hard as you can and you can
get at a minimum to second base. If I am
swinging at a ball that I've been very
patient for, I hit it as hard as I can
and I'm running to first base,
I cannot change my plan and say, "You
know what? I'm going to stop here and
not make it to second base."
It's not worth it. Traders want to find
the reason for whatever the case is to
close at a 1:1 risk to reward to lock in
their profits or to not lose out on
their profits. That wasn't part of the
plan. The plan is either you lose or you
make it to second base. If you swing
that ball and as you're running to first
base, you're seeing that it's not going
as far as you anticipated, you can't
change the plan. You need to stick to
your plan of going all the way to second
base. If for whatever reason you get
out, you get out, but you stuck to your
plan. And that is the most important
thing that you need to do so you make
back those losses and you stick to your
plan so you end up positive. Now, is
there times when you get to second base
and as soon as you get to second base,
the ball is still far or the pitcher
wasn't able to catch it and you can
squeeze in third base? Sure, do that. Or
maybe you can run all the way to fourth,
but your base is going to always be
second base. Same thing in trading. When
you take your trade, the minimum that
you need to settle for is a 1:2 risk to
reward. Once the trade gets to the one
to two risk reward, you make a decision,
okay, I'm going to continue to hold to a
one to three, potentially a one to four.
But, once you get to a one to four,
you're at your home run, trade is done,
you move on to the next one. You don't
try and run around again and do another
circle around the whole entire field. It
just doesn't make sense. You're now
being greedy, you're showing off, and it
doesn't make sense. Swing the ball, run
to home base, move on to the next one. I
just diving back into this analogy, just
like the more I think about it is it
just makes so much sense in real life.
Because trading is no different than
these analogies, and it it just becomes
so real. If I'm running to a first base,
I get through it, I get to second base,
and if I'm running to second base, and I
see that the catcher is going to catch
I'm not going to turn around and go back
to first. I commit to my second base. I
can't tell you how many times traders
have had their trade almost hits a one
to two risk reward, whatever they saw
turned them off, or they got scared, and
they closed out, and they end up they
ended up missing on a one to two, one to
three, one to four trade. You stick to
the plan, you're only moving forward,
you're not looking back. And all of this
really just comes down to one big global
plan, and you need to implement this
every single time you go play the game,
every single time you go take a trade.
Now, most importantly, attached to that,
you need to understand what you're
reading in the markets. If you have no
idea how to properly understand if a
market is bullish, ready to buy, if a
market is at a strong support or
resistance, a strong supply and demand
zone, and you don't have a right entry
signal to enter the trade, then you're
really just working backwards. You have
an idea of what to do in the markets,
but you don't really understand how to
read it. It's almost like these songs
that you don't know the language of it,
but you pretty much just jam out to it
because it sounds good. You you know, it
sounds good to listen to this music, but
you don't really know what they're
saying. You could be saying anything
crazy. Now, you have the exact same
thing when it comes to trading. You can
have the idea of yes, I get it, I need
to buy and sell when it's the right
time, but you don't have the right
strategy. And that's what I do every
single week with my students. I share
with them my top markets that I'm
interested in trading, why it makes
sense to buy versus sell, and most
importantly, where they should be
entering and how much they should be
risking, and how long it can potentially
get to the take profit. Now, if you want
to know more about this, click the link
in the description below. I'll
personally review your trades to make
sure that you're doing the correct thing
or incorrect thing, and most
importantly, that you have a plan that
you're sticking to every single week.
With that being said, ladies and
gentlemen, I hope you guys enjoyed this
video. I will see you guys in the next
one. Make sure you guys hit that like
and subscribe button. And I'll see you
guys in the next one.